<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>PHP on Garbage Collected</title>
    <link>https://guxi.me/tags/php/</link>
    <description>Recent content in PHP on Garbage Collected</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 23:11:10 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://guxi.me/tags/php/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Contextual Dependency Injection Is a Myth</title>
      <link>https://guxi.me/posts/contextual-dependency-injection-is-a-myth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 23:11:10 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guxi.me/posts/contextual-dependency-injection-is-a-myth/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes in your daily programming life, you would want to inject different object instances based on the current route or module. For example, you want to connect to Database Foo for route /foo and Database Bar for route /bar. It seems a clever idea to do what is called a &amp;ldquo;contextual binding&amp;rdquo;, aka inject instances conditionally based on some runtime value.
In Laravel it looks like this:
&amp;lt;?php $this-&amp;gt;app-&amp;gt;when(PhotoController::class) -&amp;gt;needs(Filesystem::class) -&amp;gt;give(function () { return Storage::disk(&amp;#39;local&amp;#39;); }); $this-&amp;gt;app-&amp;gt;when([VideoController::class, UploadController::class]) -&amp;gt;needs(Filesystem::class) -&amp;gt;give(function () { return Storage::disk(&amp;#39;s3&amp;#39;); });  This code looks nice and handy at first glance, but in my experience, they are often doing more harm than any good.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Never Force Yourself to Learn New Skills Without a Concrete Project</title>
      <link>https://guxi.me/posts/never-force-yourself-to-learn-new-skills-without-a-concrete-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2019 13:51:45 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guxi.me/posts/never-force-yourself-to-learn-new-skills-without-a-concrete-project/</guid>
      <description>As the job demand is going nowhere in a decade, a lot of new guys want to get into programming. There are numerous courses online, teaching a variety of skills in programming. There are also new shinning frameworks climbing up GitHub trending every day. I see a lot of people, typically newly graduated students, get confused. There seems to be an endless stream of knowledge to learn. How many skills are enough?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When Do We Need PHP</title>
      <link>https://guxi.me/posts/when-do-we-need-php/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2019 12:57:59 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guxi.me/posts/when-do-we-need-php/</guid>
      <description>When we started huijiwiki.com, PHP was the language of the choice. But it was not much a choice. MediaWiki was coded in PHP. It provided us a solid starting point to expand our idea.
Since then I have touched many languages and am moderately proficient in some of them. Among them, Go is my current favorite. Rust is the language I want to explore more.
Go as well as Rust has a very different nature compared to PHP.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>